<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Block - All about ad blockers and ad blocking.</title>
    <link>http://block.blokada.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Block - All about ad blockers and ad blocking.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://block.blokada.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating Blokada</title>
      <link>http://block.blokada.org/post/2017/06/14/translating-blokada/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://block.blokada.org/post/2017/06/14/translating-blokada/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for considering translating Blokada!
Blokada has a convenient translation system in place that is meant to make your job easier. You can find it at: go.blokada.org/translate.
Instructions Once you click the link, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a list of languages Blokada is being translated to. Click on the language you speak in order to see which phrases are translated, and which are missing or need improvement. Then click the &amp;ldquo;Sign up to help translate&amp;rdquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blokada v2.0 roadmap</title>
      <link>http://block.blokada.org/post/2017/06/08/blokada-v2.0-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://block.blokada.org/post/2017/06/08/blokada-v2.0-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been exciting several months for ad blocking on Android. When I started developing Blokada, it was just a side project of mine meant to test some less-known Android APIs and capabilities of the platform itself. At that time, the only existing ad blockers for Android were eating battery like crazy and slowing down device. Plus, they were quite cumbersome to use. I wanted to see if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to build something that will block most of the ads across all apps, while being efficient and fast enough so that I won&amp;rsquo;t notice it in terms of battery life, or network bandwidth speed or device performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://block.blokada.org/post/2016/12/13/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://block.blokada.org/post/2016/12/13/about/</guid>
      <description>The Block aims to provide you with up-to-date, detailed and complete information about ad blocking. Here you can find articles about ad blockers for all major platforms (Android, iOS, Web), app comparisons, extensions reviews, tips, as well as news from the world of never-ending arms race between ad block apps, publishers, developers and ad platforms.
We touch everything from commercial ad blockers to open source community projects and provide you with recommendations and guides so that you can also make your life ad-free.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>